<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Syed Muhammad Hamza</title>
    <link>https://syedmuhammadhamza.github.io/Hamza_Portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Syed Muhammad Hamza</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://syedmuhammadhamza.github.io/Hamza_Portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Recommendation System Web Application</title>
      <link>https://syedmuhammadhamza.github.io/Hamza_Portfolio/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syedmuhammadhamza.github.io/Hamza_Portfolio/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>Github link Deployed live application here   Overview The Regression-based Movie Recommender system that&amp;rsquo;s a hybrid of content-based and collaborative filtering Recommender system. Simply rate some movies and get immediate recommendations tailored for you
Table of contents  Live Applicaiton Live Applicaiton Accompanying Medium articles Prerequisites Project Structure Dataset Roadmap Roadmap Step Notebooks About Hybrid Algorithm  Step 1. Collaborative filtering Step 2. Content-based filtering Step 3. Prediction   Usage Contributing Contact License References  Live Applicaiton  Deployed live application here  Accompanying Medium articles  Hybrid Recommendation System Web-Application Part 1: Exploratory Data Analysis with PostgreSQL  Prerequisites The following open source packages are used in this project:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myers–Briggs Type Indicator (MBTI) classification Web Application</title>
      <link>https://syedmuhammadhamza.github.io/Hamza_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syedmuhammadhamza.github.io/Hamza_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Github link Web Application   web application screenshot   Overview During my sophomore year of bachelors, I stumbled upon a book titled &amp;ldquo;Gifts differing: understanding personality type&amp;rdquo; by Isabel Briggs Myers and Peter B. Myers through a friend I met on Reddit &amp;ldquo;This book distinguishes four categories of personality styles and shows how these qualities determine the way you perceive the world and come to conclusions about what you&amp;rsquo;ve seen&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Politician-Face-Classifier Web Application</title>
      <link>https://syedmuhammadhamza.github.io/Hamza_Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syedmuhammadhamza.github.io/Hamza_Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>GitHub link Web Application   Web Scraping  Collected images from google through web-scraping using Selenium with ChromeDriver Code Link  Data Cleaning  Performed data cleaning through face detection using OpenCV pre-trained feature-based Haar cascade classifiers to discard images from the dataset without face and two eyes visible  Feature engineering  Performed feature engineering through extraction by wavelet transformation of images using PyWavelets and then vertically stacking raw and wavelet transformed images  Model Building trained machine learning models such as Logistic Regression, SVM(Support vector machine), and Ensembling bagging Random Forest</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Consumer Finance Complaints Text classification with PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>https://syedmuhammadhamza.github.io/Hamza_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syedmuhammadhamza.github.io/Hamza_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Consumer Finance Complaints Text classification with PostgreSQL Github link Recently I came across The Consumer Complaint Database Published by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, which is a U.S. government agency, “ The Database is a collection of complaints about consumer financial products and services that they sent to companies for response. Complaints are published after the company responds, confirming a commercial relationship with the consumer, or after 15 days, whichever comes first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handwritten Digit Recognizer</title>
      <link>https://syedmuhammadhamza.github.io/Hamza_Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syedmuhammadhamza.github.io/Hamza_Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Handwritten Digit Recognizer Github link Web Application   Neural Network from scratch in Python to recognize handwritten digit achieved 98.45% test accuracy and using Keras CNN(Convolutional neural network) achieved 99.25% test accuracy deployed model to production
Dataset   Deep Neural network (DNN) Neural Network Implementation from scratch using Python
Model representation Implemented Neural network has 3 layers an input layer,a hidden layer and an output layer.   Feedforward and Regularized Cross entropy cost function Implementation of DNN includes code for Feedforward and Regularized Cross entropy cost function   Backpropagation Implementation of DNN includes code for Backpropagation     Model Performance  DNN: 98.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Cipher Application</title>
      <link>https://syedmuhammadhamza.github.io/Hamza_Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syedmuhammadhamza.github.io/Hamza_Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Github Link An Android-based application build using the MVC model That allows users to Encipher(encrypt) and Decipher( decrypt) text using using following Ciphers
 Shift Cipher Vigenere Cipher Substitution Cipher Playfair Cipher      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating soon</title>
      <link>https://syedmuhammadhamza.github.io/Hamza_Portfolio/post/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syedmuhammadhamza.github.io/Hamza_Portfolio/post/project-7/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
